Welcome back to the Image and Video Processing class. In the previous video,
欢迎来到图像和视频处理课程 在之前的视频中
we saw a number of examples that show what image and video processing can do
我们看了一些例子 展示了图像和视频处理能够为我们做的
for us. Now we are going to see a few additional
现在我们将再看一些其他的例子
examples. We're going to start again from consumer
我们这次将从大家熟悉的日常图像开始
images, images of the type that you are familar with, and then we're going to
然后我们来看一些医学图像的例子
move to a couple of examples of medical imaging, an area where image and video
这是一个图像和视频处理技术发展极为成功的领域
processing has been extremely successful and a very important area by itself.
它自己本身也是一个非常重要的领域
So once again, a couple of additional examples of consumer images and videos.
那么接下来 我们来看些日常图像和视频的例子
So this is a very interesting example of what video processing can do for us.
这是一个非常有意思的例子 关于视频处理能为我们做些什么
Let us watch this movies for a second. So here we have two kids in one video and
让我们先看一会儿这些短片 在一个短片里有两个小孩
two kids in another video doing exactly the same activity.
而另一个短片里也有两个孩子 他们参与的活动是完全一样的
We want the computer to automatically identify that, although, these are very
我们想让计算机来自动识别
different people, very different backgrounds,
尽管是完全不同的人 完全不同的背景
in completely different jumping gear, and a house in one, and no house in the
在完全不同的蹦床上 其中一个在背景里有一所房子
other in the background. We want to make sure the computer
而另一个则没有 我们想要确保计算机能够理解这些
understands that in spite of all those different things, the activity is the
虽然两个视频中有很多不同的地方
same activity. Kids keeps jumping.
但活动是一致的 孩子们一直在蹦床
We want the computer to actually be able to say that that activity is very
而我们希望计算机能识别出那个活动和这个非常不一样
different than this one, which is actually a person playing with a
这是一个人在玩一个球
ball, but this particular one should be identified to be exactly the same at this
而这个视频则应该被识别成 和这一个中的活动完全一致
other one, which is another person playing with a football.
这是另一个人在玩一个足球
So, we want the computer to automatically classify these videos for us based on
我们希望计算机按照视频中的不同活动
what activity is happening in the videos. Let's just see another very interesting
自动地将视频分类 让我们再来看另一个非常有趣的例子
example. I'm going to play this video in a second.
我一会儿将播放这个视频
If you see different frames surrounding the person,
如果你在人物周围看到有不同颜色的方框
so green and red, that would mean that the computer has identified that
比如绿色和红色 这就表明计算机已经基本识别了
basically the person is doing a different activity.
这个人在进行着不同的活动
If you see exactly the same color of the frame, so maybe both green or both red,
如果你看到了一样颜色的方框 可能都是绿色或者都是红色
means that the computer has automatically identified that the person is actually
这说明计算机自动识别出
doing the same activity or the same type of activity.
这两个人物实际在进行相同或者相同种类的活动
So let's watch this movie. So different colors, that means different
让我们来看这个短片 现在是不同的颜色 表明是不同的活动
activities. And now, same colors, meaning same
现在是相同的颜色 说明是相同的活动
And one more example.
再来看一个例子
In this case, we actually have three different persons at, at three different
在这个例子中 三行里分别有三个不同的人
rows and we have in the left, the grand truth.
在右边有大字“Truth”
That happens very often in this type of [INAUDIBLE] in image and video processing
这经常会在这类的图像和视频处理中出现
where you know what you expect, so you can verify if your algorithms are working
你知道你想要什么 所以你能够判断出算法的有效性
properly. On the right, we actually have the actual
在左边 我们有着该算法实际的结果
recite of the algorithm. And once again, if you see frames of the same color,
你再一次地可以看到一样颜色的方框
mean, means that in spite of the fact people are the different people, that
这表明虽然事实上他们是不同的人
computer has identified that they are doing exactly the same activity.
但是计算机可以识别出他们在 做着相同的动作
If you see different frames, different colors, means the computer has identified
如果你看到不同颜色的方框 这就表明计算机识别出
they're doing different activities. So let's just watch the movie.
他们在做着不同的动作 下面让我们观看短片
So look that three of them are green and now this move to yellow which means that
可以看到三个人都是绿色方框 而现在都变成了黄色
the computer understood that the person changed his or her own activity, move
这表明计算机明白 这些人改变了他们的动作
from running to jumping. So that's another thing that we want the
从跑变成了跳 这就是我们想让计算机为我们完成的另一件事
computer to do for us, to identify what's happening in the images.
即识别图像中正在发生什么
Sometimes we actually want much simpler things.
有时候我们只是需要更加简单的东西
For example, here, we might just want these very poorly acquire image to become
比如这个例子 我们只是想让这张非常糟糕的图像
this very nice image. This is something that happens to us all
变成这样非常漂亮的图像 这是很常见的事情
the time. We take an image that is not, it doesn't
我们拍摄的图片并不像我们所期望的那样好看
look as good as we want it to look. For example, this, this is an extreme
比如这个 这是一个比较极端的例子
case, We're going to understand what happened actually in this image and we
我们要理解这副图像中到底发生了什么
want to automatically, after we have taken the image, we don't want to go back
很自然地 在拍完这张图像之后 我们不想再回去重新拍摄
and take again that image. We actually want the computer do
我们希望计算机
automatically for us give us a very nice image.
为我们自动调节出一张非常棒的图像
These aren't just examples of things we are familiar with.
不只有我们熟悉事物的例子
A more complicated example is here, yet another movie, but basically what we want
这里有个更复杂些的例子 又是一个短片
is to be able to identify everything that is happening in the movie.
不过这次我们想要识别出其中发生的每一件事情
This is sometimes called computer vision and not image processing, although, the
这个有时候被叫做计算机视觉 而并非图像处理
two areas are close really, really, really close related and we are going to
虽然这两个领域非常非常的接近
discuss that during the next coming weeks.
而我们将在接下来的几周里讨论这个
All this has been about consumer imaging. Image and video processing, in
这些都和日常图像有关 图像和视频处理 尤其是图像处理
particular, image processing, but also a bit more in these recent days and recent
近一段时间变得多了起来
years, video processing is extremely important in medical and biological
视频处理在医学和生物学影像方面极其重要
images. And let me give you a couple of examples
让我给你展示几个例子
that are very exciting applications, where image and video processing can
都是关于图像和视频处理能够 在社会和健康方面产生的巨大作用
actually make tremendous impact in society and health.
的非常令人兴奋的应用
So this is a particular application. We're going to talk about this
这是其中一个例子 事实上我们将在最后一周的课程里
application, actually, the last week of the class.
讨论这个应用
And, this is a particular application that is related to neurosurgery.
这也是一个关于神经外科应用的例子
I'm going to describe this application again, as I said, in the last week of
像我之前说的那样 我将在最后一周里详细介绍这一应用
this class. But the basic idea is that the
基本的思想是有关
neurosurgeon implants in the brain an electrode and sends some excitation to
神经外科医生在大脑植入一个电极 然后激发这一电极
that electrode, and this is extremely important for many,
这对于很多很多病症极其重要
many problems, like Parkinson, tremor, depression or or, or other problems.
比如帕金森、震颤症、抑郁症等等一些病症
But a fundamental problem is that a neurosurgeon needs to see inside the
但是一个基本的难题是 一个神经外科医生需要看到大脑内部
brain, needs to know where he or she is going
需要知道在大脑的哪一部分进行手术
inside the brain. And in order to do that, we actually, in
而为了达成这一目的
order to know where to implant the electrode, and where exactly to go.
更确切说是为了知道在哪里植入电极 在哪里进行手术
The neurosurgeon will take images of our inside of the brain through MRI, CT, or
神经外科医生将通过核磁共振 (MRI) 、计算机断层扫描 (CT) 或者其他方法 拍摄大脑内部的影像
other disciplines, and try to get a map, try to get basically what we see from
并且尝试绘制出映射图 从而试着得到像我们从
Google Maps or from other images. They want to know, have a map from inside
谷歌地图或者其他图像上能看到的信息 他们想有一张我们大脑内部的地图
our brain. So they want to be able to know
从而使得他们能够知道
everything that is happening in our brain here.
在我们大脑内部发生的一切
So one of areas that they want to implant electrodes, we find it here.
我们在这里看到这是其中一个他们想植入电极的区域
So, this is the, this fancy and beautiful in color images that you see here is a
然后现在你看到的这个花哨漂亮的彩色图像
combination of multiple modalities that are used to look inside our brain.
是用来描述我们大脑内部结构的 多模态合成图像
They are put together with techniques that we are going to discuss,
使得他们合在一起的技术 我们将在后面进行讨论
and then, you can create these beautiful images that localize and also tell you
你能够创造出这些美丽的图像 来定位并且告诉你
how different parts of the brain are actually connected.
大脑的不同部分实际是怎样连接的
Once you do that, you can actually map, as I mention, you can actually map the
一旦你完成了 你就绘制出了地图 像我说的那样
brain and understand these are actually electrodes that were implanted and you
你就能实际地绘制出大脑内部图像 并且明白被植入的电极在哪里
can localize where exactly is the electrodes are touching in the brain.
然后你就能够定位出电极作用于大脑的部位
So it's really seeing inside our head and a lot of image processing needs to go
这样就真正地看到了我们头颅的内部 而在这背后需要大量的图像处理工作
behind this to make this possible. And, as I say, this is a very exciting
来使得这成为可能 像我说的 这是一个非常激动人心的领域
area, because the contribution of new image processing here is tremendous.
因为新兴图像处理在这里有着非常巨大的贡献
Similarly, we can look HIV research. Again, we're going to discuss this more,
类似地我们来看HIV (人类免疫缺陷病毒) 的研究
at the end, the last week of class. We're going to have entire lecture of
我们将在最后一周的课程中 更深入地进行讨论
this particular problem and the image processing challenges.
我们将有一整堂课关于 这一问题以及相应图像处理的挑战
So this is a, basically a virus and this is a schematic of an HIV virus. And for
这是一个病毒 这是一个HIV病毒的结构图
reasons that we're going to discuss later, we need to identify the actual
而为了我们之后会提到的原因 我们需要识别这个东西的真实形状
shape of this, this is schematic.
这是一个原理图
You might say, why is this so difficult? I'm going to show you that in just a
你可能会说 这个有什么难的吗？ 我一会儿就将展示给你看
second. The basic, idea is that we need to be
基本思想是我们需要能识别
able to identify that what I've just marked to you looks like this.
我刚刚标注给你们的看起来像这样的东西
This is a three-dimensional rendering of exactly that what's marked in the picture
这是我刚刚标注的那个东西的三维效果图
as the gp120 and the gp41. So that's what called the envelope and that's a very
叫做gp120和gp41 这就是所谓的包膜
important part of the virus that a virus uses to basically latch into the next
这是病毒的一个非常重要的组成部分 是病毒用来插入下一个细胞的
cell and identifying that shape is, is very, very important.
所以识别这一形状就非常非常重要
What's behind the scenes? So why is this so difficult?
那在这背后都有些什么呢？ 为什么会非常困难？
Because actually what you get is images like this.
因为你得到的图像是像这样的
basically this is what the schematic of what I showed you before,
这就是我之前展示给你看的那个原理图
and these are, these small envelopes I showed you before.
而这些就是你之前看到的小小的包膜
Okay? And from images like this one, you need
明白了吗？ 而从这样的图像中
to be able to do reconstructions like, like the ones I'm showing you now.
你需要能够重建出像我正在展示给你看的这些
Okay? So this is basic science that has a tremendous potential contribution into
明白了吧？ 这就是基础科学对于疫苗发展
the development of vaccines or the understanding of different viruses.
或者不同病毒研究的惊人的潜在贡献
Finally, sometimes image processing, as we saw that, that it can help
最后 像我们之前看到的 有时候图像处理
neurosurgery can help others kinds of surgery to make them safer.
能够帮助神经外科医生 以及其他的外科医生来降低手术风险
This is a particular application where it's important to understand where the
这又是一个应用 对于知道食道在哪里有重大作用
esophagus is. So, cardiac ablation which is a very
心脏消融术是一个非常常见的手术
common surgery, when it's done, it avoids basically
手术完成后 食道可以避免一些触碰
touching it and maybe damaging it. So once again, in our application of
以及可能的伤害 所以这又一次需要我们图像处理的应用
image processing, which we're going to discuss during this week.
而在这一周中我们将继续讨论
We are going to discuss different type of applications.
我们还将讨论很多其他类型的应用
We're going to touch on some of them. We won't be able to touch on all the
我们将尽力涉及其中的一些 虽然不可能涵盖当前所有的
medical imaging applications out there, but we're going to touch enough to give
医学影像应用 但是我们将尽可能多地涉及
you an idea of why image processing is so important in the area of medical imaging
来给你们一个印象 为什么图像处理对于医学影像和生物学数据如此重要
and biological data. So to conclude, we have, in these two
总结一下 我们在这两个视频中
videos, we have seen a large number of examples going from scientific data from
已经见到了大量的例子
Mars to consumer videos and images like in the movies or like images that you, we
从科学数据、火星探测 到日常视频和图像 就像我们在短片中看到的
take with our own cameras all the way to medical imaging.
那些我们自己平常拍摄的 一直到医学影像
And we're going to discuss during the next, nine weeks starting with this week,
而从这周到接下来的九周时间里 我们将讨论
the basic techniques that we need to be able to achieve all what, we've just seen
实现这些需要的基础技术
that we want or we need to do with images.
而我们已经看到我们想要 或者需要对图像做的
So, see you in the next video.
那么 下一个视频再见 //教育无边界字幕组  林小七Lynn | luoyetx | wugui那么 下一个视频再见 //果壳教育无边界字幕组  林小七Lynn | luoyetx | wugui